A Guide to the Old Dominion University Literary Festival, 1978-
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Digitized Video 1978-2003
  - Compact Discs (CD's) 1978-2003
    - 15th Annual Literary Festival 1992
      - Who All Killed Cock Robin? Play by William Patrick. Adapted by W.D. Snodgrass and DeLoss McGraw. Part 1 7:30 pm 4 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:1 of 16)
      - Who All Killed Cock Robin? Play by William Patrick. Adapted by W.D. Snodgrass and DeLoss McGraw. Part 2 7:30 pm 4 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:2 of 16)
      - Who All Killed Cock Robin? Play by William Patrick. Adapted by W.D. Snodgrass and DeLoss McGraw. Part 3 7:30 pm 4 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:3 of 16)
      - Words at Play: A Panel Performance on Childhood and Literature. Jean Fritz, Jay O'Callahan, W.D. Snodgrass, Fred Chappell, and Kathryn Morton. Part 1 11:00 am 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:4 of 16)
      - Words at Play: A Panel Performance on Childhood and Literature. Jean Fritz, Jay O'Callahan, W.D. Snodgrass, Fred Chappell, and Kathryn Morton. Part 2 11:00 am 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:5 of 16)
      - Words at Play: A Panel Performance on Childhood and Literature. Jean Fritz, Jay O'Callahan, W.D. Snodgrass, Fred Chappell, and Kathryn Morton. Part 3 11:00 am 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:6 of 16)
      - Words at Play: A Panel Performance on Childhood and Literature. Jean Fritz, Jay O'Callahan, W.D. Snodgrass, Fred Chappell, and Kathryn Morton. Part 4 11:00 am 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:7 of 16)
      - A Staged Reading of Reverse Thunder: A Dramatic Poem by Diane Ackerman. Part 1 7:30 pm 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:8 of 16)
      - A Staged Reading of Reverse Thunder: A Dramatic Poem by Diane Ackerman. Part 2 7:30 pm 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:9 of 16)
      - A Staged Reading of Reverse Thunder: A Dramatic Poem by Diane Ackerman. Part 3 7:30 pm 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:10 of 16)
      - Paul West: Fiction Reading from The women of Whitechapel and Jack the Ripper 7:30 pm 6 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:11 of 16)
      - W.D. Snodgrass & Kathy Snodgrass: Poetry Reading and Slideshow from W.D.'s Midnight Carnival 11:00 am 7 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:12 of 16)
      - Jay O'Callahan: The Art of Storytelling 7:30 pm 7 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:13 of 16)
      - Charles Johnson: Fiction Reading. Part 1 7:30 pm 8 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:14 of 16)
      - Charles Johnson: Fiction Reading. Part 2 7:30 pm 8 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:15 of 16)
      - John Toomey: Original Jazz Performance 7:30 pm 8 October 1992, CD (Othertype 11:16 of 16)
    - 18th Annual Literary Festival 1995
      - Synthesis Motion Theater. Introduction by Evelina Galang 11:00 am 3 October 1995, CD (Othertype 11:1 of 15)
      - Fiona Cheong. Fiction 11:00 am 3 October 1995, CD (Othertype 11:2 of 15)
      - Quraysh Ali. Poetry 1:00 pm 3 October 1995, CD (Othertype 11:3 of 15)
      - When Political Struggle in Literature Stops Being Literature. Dana Heller, Agha Shahid Ali, Quaraysh Ali, and Evan Boland. Part 1 3:00 pm 3 October 1995, CD (Othertype 11:4 of 15)
      - When Political Struggle in Literature Stops Being Literature. Dana Heller, Agha Shahid Ali, Quaraysh Ali, and Evan Boland. Part 2 3:00 pm 3 October 1995, CD (Othertype 11:5 of 15)
      - Hymn for the Fainthearted Dance and Poetry by Evan Boland 7:45 pm 3 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:6 of 15)
      - Tim Seibles. Poetry 11:00 am 4 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:7 of 15)
      - Agha Shahid Ali. Poetry. Part 1 3:00 pm 4 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:8 of 15)
      - Agha Shahid Ali. Poetry. Part 2 3:00 pm 4 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:9 of 15)
      - Ninotchka Rosca. Fiction Reading 8:00 pm 4 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:10 of 15)
      - Mary Crow. Poetry. Part 1 11:00 am 5 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:11 of 15)
      - Mary Crow. Poetry. Part 2 11:00 am 5 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:12 of 15)
      - Silencing of Women: Direct and Indirect Censorship. Ninotchka Rosca 3:00 pm 5 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:13 of 15)
      - Illocana United Youth Dance Troupe 7:45 pm 5 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:14 of 15)
      - Ariel Dorfman. Fiction 8:00 pm 5 October 1995, CD (Othertype 12:15 of 15)
    - 20th Annual Literary Festival 1997
      - Cornelius Eady. Poetry. Part 1 10:00 am 14 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:1 of 25)
      - Cornelius Eady. Poetry. Part 2 10:00 am 14 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:2 of 25)
      - Melissa Faye Green. Non-fiction 3:00 pm 14 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:3 of 25)
      - Mike D'Orso. Journalism and Non-Fiction. Part 1 10:00 am 15 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:4 of 25)
      - Mike D'Orso. Journalism and Non-Fiction. Part 2 10:00 am 15 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:5 of 25)
      - Liz Waldner. Poetry 2:00 pm 15 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:6 of 25)
      - What kind of Fire: Three Genres, Three Truths? Liz Waldner, Reginald McKnight, and Melissa Fay Greene. Part 1 3:30 pm 15 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:7 of 25)
      - What kind of Fire: Three Genres, Three Truths? Liz Waldner, Reginald McKnight, and Melissa Fay Greene. Part 2 3:30 pm 15 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:8 of 25)
      - Reginald McKnight. Fiction. Part 1 10:00 am 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:9 of 25)
      - Reginald McKnight. Fiction. Part 2 10:00 am 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:10 of 25)
      - Race, Culture, Rage and Compassion by Martin Espada. Part 1 2:00 pm 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:11 of 25)
      - Race, Culture, Rage and Compassion by Martin Espada. Part 2 2:00 pm 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:12 of 25)
      - Race, Culture, Rage and Compassion by Martin Espada. Part 3 2:00 pm 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:13 of 25)
      - Race, Culture, Rage and Compassion by Martin Espada. Part 4 2:00 pm 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:14 of 25)
      - Race, Culture, Rage and Compassion by Martin Espada. Part 5 2:00 pm 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:15 of 25)
      - Louise Redd. Fiction 3:30 pm 16 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:16 of 25)
      - Marita Golden. Fiction. Part 1 10:00 am 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:17 of 25)
      - Marita Golden. Fiction. Part 2 10:00 am 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:18 of 25)
      - Richard Hell. Fiction. Part 1 2:00 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 12:19 of 25)
      - Richard Hell. Fiction. Part 2 2:00 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 13:20 of 25)
      - The Rub Between Fiction and Non-Fiction. Richard Hell, Gay Talese, Mike D'Orso, Louise Redd. Part 1 3:30 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 13:21 of 25)
      - The Rub Between Fiction and Non-Fiction. Richard Hell, Gay Talese, Mike D'Orso, Louise Redd. Part 2 3:30 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 13:22 of 25)
      - The Rub Between Fiction and Non-Fiction. Richard Hell, Gay Talese, Mike D'Orso, Louise Redd. Part 3 3:30 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 13:23 of 25)
      - Gay Telese. Non-fiction. Part 1 8:00 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 13:24 of 25)
      - Gay Telese. Non-fiction. Part 2 8:00 pm 17 October 1997, CD (Othertype 13:25 of 25)
    - 21st Annual Literary Festival 1998
      - Tony Grooms. Fiction and Poetry 2:00 pm 6 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:1 of 22)
      - Jane Bernstein. Non-fiction 3:30 pm 6 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:2 of 22)
      - Robert Pinsky. Part 1 8:00 pm 6 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:3 of 22)
      - Robert Pinsky. Part 2 8:00 pm 6 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:4 of 22)
      - Robert Pinsky. Part 3 8:00 pm 6 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:5 of 22)
      - Jacqueline Woodson. Fiction 10:00 am 7 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:6 of 22)
      - Jack Myers. Poetry 2:00 pm 7 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:7 of 22)
      - Jack Myers. Poetry 2:00 pm 7 October 1998, CD -- copy (Othertype 13:8 of 22)
      - Saying What You Mean: The Art of Honesty. Jack Myers and Jacqueline Woodson. Part 1 10:00 am 7 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:9 of 22)
      - Saying What You Mean: The Art of Honesty. Jack Myers and Jacqueline Woodson. Part 2 10:00 am 7 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:10 of 22)
      - Saying What You Mean: The Art of Honesty. Jack Myers and Jacqueline Woodson. Part 1 10:00 am 7 October 1998, CD -- copy (Othertype 13:11 of 22)
      - Saying What You Mean: The Art of Honesty. Jack Myers and Jacqueline Woodson. Part 2 10:00 am 7 October 1998, CD -- copy (Othertype 13:12 of 22)
      - Nicole Brossard. Poetry, fiction, and non-fiction. Part 1 8:00 pm 7 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:13 of 22)
      - Nicole Brossard. Poetry, fiction, and non-fiction. Part 2 8:00 pm 7 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:14 of 22)
      - Scott Cairns. Poetry 10:00 am 8 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:15 of 22)
      - Open Mike. Part 1 11:00 am 8 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:16 of 22)
      - Open Mike. Part 2 11:00 am 8 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:17 of 22)
      - Tony Hoagland. Poetry 2:00 pm 8 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:18 of 22)
      - A New Dialogue: Asian and Asian-American Writers in America. Li-Young Lee and Maria Luisa Carino. Part 1 3:30 pm 8 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:19 of 22)
      - A New Dialogue: Asian and Asian-American Writers in America. Li-Young Lee and Maria Luisa Carino. Part 2 3:30 pm 8 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:20 of 22)
      - Sena Naslund. Fiction. Part 1 2:00 pm 9 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:21 of 22)
      - Sena Naslund. Fiction. Part 2 2:00 pm 9 October 1998, CD (Othertype 13:22 of 22)
    - 22nd Annual Literary Festival 1999
      - Phillip Raisor: Overview of the Literary Festival; Michael Pearson: Review of the 22nd Annual Literary Festival; Gary Short: Introduction to Rita Dove; and Michael Pearson: Closing Remarks October 1999, CD (Othertype 13:1 of 1)
    - 23rd Annual Literary Festival 2000
      - Tim O'Brien. Part 1 8:00 pm 3 October 2000, CD (Othertype 14:1 of 5)
      - Tim O'Brien. Part 2 8:00 pm 3 October 2000, CD (Othertype 14:2 of 5)
      - Tim O'Brien. Part 3 8:00 pm 3 October 2000, CD (Othertype 14:3 of 5)
      - MFA Faculty Reading. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Gary Short. Part 1 4:00 pm 6 October 2000, CD (Othertype 14:4 of 5)
      - MFA Faculty Reading. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Gary Short. Part 2 4:00 pm 6 October 2000, CD (Othertype 14:5 of 5)
    - 24th Annual Literary Festival 2001
      - Festival Preview: Roberly Bell 2:30 pm 30 September 2001, CD (Othertype 14:1 of 24)
      - Graduates of ODU MFA Program: Terry Perrel, Temple West, Tom Yuill. Part 1 4:00 pm 1 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:2 of 24)
      - Graduates of ODU MFA Program: Terry Perrel, Temple West, Tom Yuill. Part 2 4:00 pm 1 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:3 of 24)
      - Roseann Runte. Part 1 8:00 pm 1 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:4 of 24)
      - Roseann Runte. Part 2 8:00 pm 1 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:5 of 24)
      - Agyma Kamau 2:00 pm 2 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:6 of 24)
      - Sheryl St. Germain 4:00 pm 2 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:7 of 24)
      - Holly Hughes. Part 1 8:00 pm 2 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:8 of 24)
      - Holly Hughes. Part 2 8:00 pm 2 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:9 of 24)
      - Eugene Gloria 4:00 pm 3 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:10 of 24)
      - Marjorie Agosin. Part 1 8:00 pm 3 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:11 of 24)
      - Marjorie Agosin. Part 2 8:00 pm 3 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:12 of 24)
      - Joseph Skibell. Part 1 4:00 pm 4 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:13 of 24)
      - Joseph Skibell. Part 2 4:00 pm 4 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:14 of 24)
      - Greg Bottoms. Part 1 2:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:15 of 24)
      - Greg Bottoms. Part 2 2:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:16 of 24)
      - Greg Bottoms. Part 3 2:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:17 of 24)
      - Karen McElmurray. Part 1 4:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:18 of 24)
      - Karen McElmurray. Part 2 4:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:19 of 24)
      - Dorothy Allison. Part 1 8:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:20 of 24)
      - Dorothy Allison. Part 2 8:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:21 of 24)
      - Dorothy Allison. Part 3 8:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:22 of 24)
      - Dorothy Allison. Part 4 8:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:23 of 24)
      - Dorothy Allison. Part 5 8:00 pm 5 October 2001, CD (Othertype 14:24 of 24)
    - 25th Annual Literary Festival 2002
      - Writing Women's Voices. Debra Bruce and Lenore Hart. Part 1 2:00 pm 30 September 2002, CD (Othertype 15:1 of 31)
      - Writing Women's Voices. Debra Bruce and Lenore Hart. Part 2 2:00 pm 30 September 2002, CD (Othertype 15:2 of 31)
      - The Round Square: Readings in a Fluid Box. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Brian Silberman. Part 1 8:00 pm 30 September 2002, CD (Othertype 15:3 of 31)
      - The Round Square: Readings in a Fluid Box. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Brian Silberman. Part 2 8:00 pm 30 September 2002, CD (Othertype 15:4 of 31)
      - Poem as Community, Community as Poem. Universes -- Gamel Abdel Chasten, Lemon, Flaco Navaja, Steven Sapp, and Mildred Ruiz. Part 1 12:30 pm 1 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:5 of 31)
      - Poem as Community, Community as Poem. Universes -- Gamel Abdel Chasten, Lemon, Flaco Navaja, Steven Sapp, and Mildred Ruiz. Part 2 12:30 pm 1 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:6 of 31)
      - Readings Across the Color Lines. Wanda Coleman and Gregory H. Williams. Part 1 8:00 pm 1 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:7 of 31)
      - Readings Across the Color Lines. Wanda Coleman and Gregory H. Williams. Part 2 8:00 pm 1 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:8 of 31)
      - Creative Non-fiction. The Prismatic Genre. David Fenza, Philip Gerard, and Valerie Miner. Part 1 11:00 am 2 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:9 of 31)
      - Creative Non-fiction. The Prismatic Genre. David Fenza, Philip Gerard, and Valerie Miner. Part 2 11:00 am 2 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:10 of 31)
      - An Association of Readers. Allison Joseph, Pablo Medina, and Mark Winegardner. Part 1 2:00 pm 2 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:11 of 31)
      - An Association of Readers. Allison Joseph, Pablo Medina, and Mark Winegardner. Part 2 2:00 pm 2 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:12 of 31)
      - An Evening of Translation and Performance. W.D. Snodgrass, Steve Kelley, Frederick Lubich, Marilyn Marloff, Agnes Mobley-Wynne, Peter Schulman, and Lee Teply. Part 1 8:00 pm 2 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:13 of 31)
      - An Evening of Translation and Performance. W.D. Snodgrass, Steve Kelley, Frederick Lubich, Marilyn Marloff, Agnes Mobley-Wynne, Peter Schulman, and Lee Teply. Part 2 8:00 pm 2 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:14 of 31)
      - Re-reading the Literary Festival. Evelina Galang, William B. Patrick, Peggy Shumaker, and Wayne Ude. Part 1 11:00 am 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:15 of 31)
      - Re-reading the Literary Festival. Evelina Galang, William B. Patrick, Peggy Shumaker, and Wayne Ude. Part 2 11:00 am 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:16 of 31)
      - Re-reading the Literary Festival. Evelina Galang, William B. Patrick, Peggy Shumaker, and Wayne Ude. Part 3 11:00 am 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:17 of 31)
      - Forging the Individual Mind. Mark Doty. Part 1 2:00 pm 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:18 of 31)
      - Forging the Individual Mind. Mark Doty. Part 2 2:00 pm 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:19 of 31)
      - President's Lecture Series. Susan Sontag. Part 1 8:00 pm 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:20 of 31)
      - President's Lecture Series. Susan Sontag. Part 2 8:00 pm 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:21 of 31)
      - President's Lecture Series. Susan Sontag. Part 3 8:00 pm 3 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:22 of 31)
      - Given that the Painter is a Poet, the Poet a Painter. Mark Doty, W.D. Snodgrass, Donald Roller Wilson, and Linda McGreevy. Part 1 11:00 am 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:23 of 31)
      - Given that the Painter is a Poet, the Poet a Painter. Mark Doty, W.D. Snodgrass, Donald Roller Wilson, and Linda McGreevy. Part 2 11:00 am 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:24 of 31)
      - Reinventing Nature. Barbara Hurd, Robert Richardson, Marjorie Sandor, and Tom Robotham. Part 1 2:00 pm 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:25 of 31)
      - Reinventing Nature. Barbara Hurd, Robert Richardson, Marjorie Sandor, and Tom Robotham. Part 2 2:00 pm 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:26 of 31)
      - Reinventing Nature. Barbara Hurd, Robert Richardson, Marjorie Sandor, and Tom Robotham. Part 3 2:00 pm 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:27 of 31)
      - Virginia Deep in the Bones. R.H.W. Dillard, George Garrett, Henry Taylor, and Ellen Bryant Voigt. Part 1 8:00 pm 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:28 of 31)
      - Virginia Deep in the Bones. R.H.W. Dillard, George Garrett, Henry Taylor, and Ellen Bryant Voigt. Part 2 8:00 pm 4 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:29 of 31)
      - A Final Celebration. Stephen Dunn. Part 1 8:00 pm 5 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:30 of 31)
      - A Final Celebration. Stephen Dunn. Part 2 8:00 pm 5 October 2002, CD (Othertype 15:31 of 31)
    - 26th Annual Literary Festival 2003
      - Rhoda Stamell 2:00 pm 30 September 2003, CD (Othertype 16:1 of 12)
      - Jamie Callan. Part 1 8:00 pm 30 September 2003, CD (Othertype 16:2 of 12)
      - Jamie Callan. Part 2 8:00 pm 30 September 2003, CD (Othertype 16:3 of 12)
      - Paul Miller, a.k.a. DJ Spooky that Subliminal Kid. Part 1 12:00 pm 1 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:4 of 12)
      - Paul Miller, a.k.a. DJ Spooky that Subliminal Kid. Part 2 12:00 pm 1 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:5 of 12)
      - Michael Pearson and Phil Raisor. Part 1 2:00 pm 1 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:6 of 12)
      - Michael Pearson and Phil Raisor. Part 2 2:00 pm 1 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:7 of 12)
      - Rick Skwiot. Part 1 10:00 am 2 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:8 of 12)
      - Rick Skwiot. Part 2 10:00 am 2 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:9 of 12)
      - Marilyn Chin 11:00 am 3 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:10 of 12)
      - Peter Meinke. Part 1 3:00 pm 3 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:11 of 12)
      - Peter Meinke. Part 2 3:00 pm 3 October 2003, CD (Othertype 16:12 of 12)
  - Other Media 1999
    While most digitized video is stored on compact discs, video from the 22nd Festival is stored on a Jazz disc. This year's video consists of the Rita Dove Final Event with Philip Raisor, Mike Pearson, and Gary Short. The original date of recording is October 15, 1999. It was migrated to a digital format on March 1, 2000.
    - 22nd Annual Literary Festival 1999
      - Rita Dove Final Event (with Philip Raisor, Mike Pearson, Gary Short) 8:00 pm 15 October 1999, Jazz. Transcribed March 1, 2000. (Othertype 16:1 of 1)